Dare ni mo miserarenai mono
My head is full of things
Atama no naka afurete
That I can never tell anybody of
In this perfect world
Machigai sae mo nai sekai he
I roam, a lost being
Mayoikonderu
Arienai hodo surikomareteru
This world is impossibly hard on me
It's an illusion that plays out before my eyes
Me ni mieru mono dake no "sekai" genshou
Abakidaseru kana
Can I find its faults?
Plastic tac tic
Plastic, all is plastic
Mou dare mo okashiku narenai yo
Nobody is allowed to be insane
Kisama mo plastic beautiful world
You're made of plastic too, like this beautiful world
In this beautiful world
Utsukushi sugiru sekai ni
Boku wa nazeka
There is something
Hikari ga mienakute
That obscures all light for me
Haretsu shite yuku kokoro ga
My heart tries to break out
And finds no answer
Mugen no rifurekushon
Secret kills for you
Shit!
くそっ!
Secret kills for you
Secret remains for you
The secret remains for you
Don't show me a dark future
Misekake no iro to
Mirai wo abakanai de
Nor a world of pretense
Keep it secret motion
Keep our motion secret
You fought quite well, considering your wounds.
その傷で　よくやるもんだ
They must have realized it the
moment they set eyes on each other.
きっと彼らは 一目見て分かったはずだ
That this destiny had awaited them
since long before they had even met.
２人は初めて出会うより　以前から…
ああなる運命だったんだろう
They were not like mere ships passing in the night.
すれ違っていたわけでもない
They understood each other better than anyone else,
彼らは誰よりも深く　お互いを理解し
and each was focused solely on the other.
相手のことだけを　見詰めていた
You are Kougami Shinya.
お前は狡噛慎也だ
You are Makishima Shougo!
お前は槙島聖護だ
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:草泥马 知音   校对:西西   后期:时末
#01: Crime Coefficient
This is the Criminal Investigation
Department, part of the Public Safety Bureau.
Access to this block is currently restricted to ensure safety.
こちらは公安局刑事課です
現在　この区画は安全のために立ち入りが制限されています
All residents of this neighborhood
are expected to evacuate immediately.
I repeat.
繰り返しお伝えします
近隣住民の皆さんは速やかに退去してください
This is the Criminal Investigation
Department, part of the Public Safety Bureau.
こちらは公安局刑事課です
Access to this block is currently restricted to ensure safety.
現在　この区画は安全のために立ち入りが制限されています
I-I'm sorry!
す　すいません
All residents of this neighborhood are expected to evacuate immediately.
A
Inspector
Excuse me! Are you Inspector Ginoza?
あの 監視官の宜野座さんでしょうか
That's me.
俺だ
You've got rotten luck, having to deal
with an incident right after getting posted.
配属早々に事件とは災難だったな
I'm Tsunemori Akane. I've been assigned to the CID as of today.
本日付けで刑事課に配属になりました常守朱です
Pleased to meet—
どうぞ　よろしく
Sorry, but the CID is very short on manpower.
悪いが 刑事課の人手不足は深刻でね
So you'll have to hit the ground running.
新米扱いはしていられない
Our target is Okura Nobuo.
対象は大倉信夫
A street scanner flagged him while doing a Hue Check,
街頭スキャナーで色相チェックに引っ掛かり
so a Security Drone ordered him to receive therapy,
セキュリティードローンがセラピーを要求したが
but he refused and ran.
拒絶して逃亡
The Psycho-Pass it recorded for him was forest green.
記録したサイコパスはフォレストグリーン
His aggression and compulsion are expected to be high.
高い攻撃性と強迫観念が予想される
Why would he avoid treatment long
enough for his Hue to get this cloudy?
そんなに色相が濁るまで治療を受けなかったなんて
It's also possible that he used incompatible drugs.
不適合薬物に手を出した可能性もある
In any case, he's a latent criminal; one far enough
gone that we don't need to wait for Sibyl Judgement.
何にせよ　シビュラ判定を待つまでもない潜在犯だ
The problem is that the place Okura ran to...
厄介なのは　大倉が逃げ込んだ
is this block.
このブロックだ
Since this is an abolition block, there's
no relay device, so Drones can't come in.
廃棄区画で中継器がないため
ドローンが進入できない
In addition...
それと 逃亡の途中で大倉は
I heard Okura abducted a passerby and is holding her hostage.
通行人を拉致して人質にしているらしい
人質が!?
A hostage?!
According to a witness, it's a young woman.
目撃者の証言によれば若い女性だそうだ
We haven't been able to confirm her identity yet.
身元の確認はまだ取れていない
What about evacuating the residents?
住民の退去は
Records state this is an uninhabited block,
登録上は無人区画だが
but because of that, it's become a den of homeless people.
おかげで浮浪者の巣窟だ
Be prepared.
覚悟しておけ
A paddy wagon...
護送車…
Don't think that the guys you're about to meet are human like us.
これから会う連中を
同じ人間と思うな
Their Psycho-Pass Crime Coefficients all exceed a specific value.
やつらはサイコパスの犯罪係数が規定値を超えた
They are people of bankrupt character.
人格破綻者だ
Normally, they would be completely isolated as latent criminals,
本来ならば　潜在犯として隔離されるべきところを
but they're allowed into the outside world for the sole purpose
ただ一つ許可された社会活動として
of flushing out criminals just like themselves.
同じ犯罪者を駆り立てる役目を与えられた
They're hunting dogs.
やつらは猟犬
They're beasts used to hunt beasts.
獣を狩るための獣だ
They're what we call "Enforcers".
それが執行官 君が預かる部下たちだ
They'll be your subordinates.
Is that cutie the newbie that everyone's been talking about, Gino?
そっちのかわい子ちゃんが噂の新入りさんっすか
ギノさん
This is Inspector Tsunemori Akane.
常守朱監視官だ
Starting today, she's your second owner.
今日から貴様らにとって ２人目の飼い主になる
P-Pleased to meet you!
よ　よろしくお願いします!
You guys all looked through the target's data, right?
全員　対象のデータには目を通してあるな
We're going to tighten the noose around our cornered rat.
今から袋のねずみをさらに締めつぶす
We'll divide into two groups and take turns.
二手に分かれて順繰りに行く
Kunizuka and Kagari, come with me.
六合塚と縢は俺と来い
The other two...
あとの２人は
will accompany Inspector Tsunemori.
常守監視官に同伴しろ
Roger.
了解
What?! I wanna go with the cutie!
俺はかわい子ちゃんと一緒がいいっす
Geez, no comeback? He's unbelievable.
ゲッ　ツッコミなしとかマジありえねえ
It wasn't funny in the first place.
スベってるのよ
Later!
まったね～
Well... Um... What should I do?
えっと　あの　どうすれば
You could order us to stand by.
あんたが待機を命令してくれれば
We wouldn't have any problems with that.
それで何の問題もないんだが
You oughta earn your paycheck, pops.
給料泥棒はやめときな とっつあん。
Hey, don't look so nervous, young lady.
まあ そう緊張しなさんな　お嬢さん
You know how to use a Dominator, right?
ドミネーターの扱いは分かるよな
I-I did receive training on it, more or less...
い　一応研修は
This is a gun that reads the
Psycho-Pass of the target you're aiming at.
こいつは狙った相手のサイコパスを読み取る銃だ
Its safety is released only when the target is a latent criminal.
相手が潜在犯だった場合のみセーフティーが解除される
You can just do what the Dominator tells you.
全部ドミネーターの言いなりになって
If it says shoot, just shoot.
撃てと言われた相手を撃ちゃいい
"Just shoot"?
撃てばいいって
If it's set to basic mode, it'll use Paralyzer.
基本モードならパラライザーだ
It'll only paralyze the target, so we'll
take them into custody and that'll be that.
撃たれても動けなくなるだけだから
それで身柄確保して一件落着
Well, you don't have to take it too seriously.
何　難しく考えることはない
Dominator Portable Psychological
Diagnosis and Suppression System
「携帯型心理診断」
「鎮圧執行システム ドミネーター起動しました」
has been activated.
User authentication: Inspector Tsunemori Akane.
「ユーザー認証　常守朱監視官」
Affiliation: Public Safety Bureau,
Criminal Investigation Department.
「公安局刑事課所属 使用許諾確認」
Dominator usage approval confirmed.
You are a valid user.
「適正ユーザーです」
Oh, that.
あ～ それな　志向性音声だから
The current enforcement mode is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
It's a directional voice, so only the holder of the gun can hear it.
握ってるあんたにしか聞こえんよ
Don't worry about it.
気にするな 最初は小うるさいだろうが
Aim calmly and disable the target.
It might be annoying at first, but you'll get used to it soon.
そのうち慣れる
What about a briefing?
ブリーフィングは
段取りの打ち合わせとかしないんでしょうか
Aren't we going to have a meeting and come up with a plan?
We'll hunt the prey and you'll observe.
俺たちが獲物を狩り あんたが見届ける
That's all there is to it.
それだけのことだ
Um, could you go into a bit more detail?
いや　もうちょっと具体的に
What he's saying is, leave it to us.
まあ　任せとけってことだ
We might not look like it, but we're experts.
俺たちも こう見えても専門家だからな
We have our own way of doing things.
俺たちには俺たちの流儀がある
But the one who's responsible for our actions is you, the Inspector.
だが　その責任を負うのは監視官であるあんただ
So if you have a problem with the way I do things,
だから俺のやり口が気に入らないときは
use that gun to shoot me.
そいつで俺を撃て
Wha...
なっ
We're latent criminals too, just like the target.
俺たちも対象と同じ潜在犯だ
The Dominator will work on us as well.
ドミネーターは作動する
Oh, we haven't introduced ourselves yet.
あ～紹介が遅れたな
That stubborn fool is Kougami Shinya.
あのとうへんぼくは狡噛慎也
And I'm Masaoka Tomomi.
でもって　俺は征陸智己
Looking forward to working with you, young lady.
よろしく頼むよ　お嬢さん
Y-Yes...
は　はあ
Well then, shall we go?
さて　じゃあ　行くかね
Up until today, I did everything by the book.
俺はな　今日まで誰よりも真面目にやってきた
I spent my whole life walking on eggshells,
誰も怒らせないように誰の迷惑にもならないように
trying my hardest not to upset or bother anyone.
おびえてビクビクしながら精いっぱいやってきた
And yet, I get flagged by one little detector and boom!
なのに　たった１回検知器に引っ掛かっただけで
They already treat me like I'm a criminal.
もう犯罪者扱いだ
This is it for me. Now that it's come to this, it's all over.
もうおしまいだ こうなっちまったら最後
I'll never be able to get a job, get married, or anything else.
就職も結婚も望みなんか　ありゃしねえ
Well, fine then.
だったらいいさ
I've restrained myself all this time.
これまで我慢してきた分好き放題にやってやる
So now, I'll just do whatever I want. I'll take whatever I want.
欲しい物はぶん取る
I'll kill anyone I don't like!
気に入らねえやつはぶち殺す
P-Please don't.
や　やめて
I've always wanted...
あんたみてえなカワイイ女
to have sex with a pretty woman like you.
一度でいいから 抱いてみたいと思ってたのさ
With a real, flesh-and-blood woman, not a virtual one.
バーチャルじゃねえ 本物の肉の女をな
Kantou Chinese Restaurant
I wonder where Kougami went.
狡噛さん どこ行っちゃったんでしょう
Crime Coefficient is under 60.
「犯罪係数　アンダー６０」
Not a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象ではありません」
The trigger will be locked.
「トリガーをロックします」
Crime Coefficient is over 120.
「犯罪係数　オーバー１２０」
An Enforcer registered at the Criminal Investigation Department.
「刑事課登録執行官 任意執行対象です」
This target has Enforce At Will status.
The safety will be released.
「セーフティーを解除します」
So he really is a latent criminal...
本当に潜在犯なんだ　この人も
And yet, he seemed pretty normal.
あんなに普通にしゃべってたのに
I've heard rumors about you.
お嬢ちゃんの噂は聞いてるぜ
They say you were the top student at the academy.
訓練所じゃ 首席だったそうじゃないか
Well, kinda...
ええ　まあ
I'll give you some friendly advice.
老婆心で言っとくが
Just forget everything you learned there.
あそこで教わったことは全部忘れた方がいい
None of that stuff is any use when you're actually working on a case.
現場じゃ　何の役にも立たんよ
Sounds irrational, right?
理不尽だと思うかい
Get used to it. Our work's full of things that defy all logic.
ところがな
そもそも俺たちの仕事ってのは理不尽の塊なんだ
People's thoughts, wishes, hopes and desires...
誰が何を思い　何を願うのか
We live in a time where technology can read everything in your mind,
人の心の全てが機械で見通せる時代だってのに
and yet, the world teems with people
who hate, lie, steal, and try to harm others.
それでも　誰かを憎んだりだましたり
傷つけようとする連中がわんさといる
If that's not irrational, then what is it?
これが理不尽じゃなくて何なんだ？
Everything you've been taught is based on theories and logic.
あんたが教わってきた事柄は全て
理詰めのセオリーだ
Soon, you'll likely come to realize how pointless they are.
それがどれだけ無意味なもんか
すぐに思い知る羽目になるだろうさ
Well, at least be prepared.
まあ　覚悟だけはしておくんだな
I...
私は
This is Hound 4.
こちらハウンド４
I found the target on the fourth floor
of the KT Building. What are your orders?
ＫＴビル４階で対象を発見 どうします
Stay there and keep an eye on him.
よし　そのまま目を離すな
Hound 2 and I will box him in.
ハウンド２と俺が包囲する
Okay.
うん
But considering how worked up he is,
でも やっこさんのテンパり具合だと
the girl he took as a hostage may be at the end of her rope.
人質の子が限界っぽいっすよ
Should I go in by myself and secure him?
俺一人で確保行っちゃいます
Okay. Don't mess it up.
よし　しくじるなよ
Roger.
了解
Crime Coefficient is over 190.
「犯罪係数　オーバー１９０」
He's a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象です」
My, my... What a bad boy.
The safety will be released.
おやおや　悪い子だ
Kagari! What are you doing?
縢　何をやっている
The Paralyzer isn't working!
パラライザーが効かねえ
He's on stimulants or something!
野郎　興奮剤か何かキメてやがる
Target's Threat Judgment has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
「執行モード リーサル·エリミネーター」
Shit!
くそっ!
Well I'll be.
Th-This is...
こ　これって
An Oracle by the Sibyl System.
シビュラシステムのご託宣だ
It says that Okura Nobuo is no longer someone who's needed in this world.
大倉信夫はもうこの世にいらない人間なんだとさ
Oh no... All this because he was detected by a street scanner?
そんな　ただ街頭スキャナーに検知されただけなのに
He probably drove himself into a corner.
自分で自分を追い込んじまったんだろうな
いまさらセラピーも何も通用しない
Nothing, not even therapy, will work on him anymore.
更生の余地なし
The judgment on him is that there's no room for rehabilitation.
そう判定されちまったんだ
It's unfortunate that your first case had
to be such an unpleasant one, young lady.
初陣で嫌な事件に当たっちまったな　お嬢ちゃん
My Psycho-Pass has become so cloudy that it looks like mud.
俺のサイコパス こんなに濁っちまってよ
もう泥みてえじゃねえか
What's more, your Psycho-Pass looks just like mine now.
おい　あんたのサイコパスも
もう俺のとそっくりじゃねえか
You and I are alike.
てめえも俺と同類だ
If they catch you, it'll be all over for you too.
やつらに捕まったら終わりだ
You'll be tortured by them as a latent criminal for the rest of your life.
死ぬまで一生潜在犯として拷問され続けるんだぜ
We'd better resolve this quickly, or it'll be all over for the hostage.
とっとと片付けないと 人質の娘がヤバいことになる
It's a Psycho-Hazard, right?
サイコハザード　ですか
Yeah. A Crime Coefficient can be contagious.
ああ 犯罪係数は伝染するからな
Young people these days aren't good at dealing with stress,
今どきの若いもんはストレスに耐性がないから
so they're easily affected by violent urges and compulsions.
暴力衝動や強迫観念の影響を受けやすい
I wrote a thesis on that topic.
私　そのテーマで論文書きました
Let me tell you one thing, young lady. It could happen to any of us.
言っとくが　明日はわが身だぞ お嬢ちゃん
The reason we were made Enforcers in the first place is...
そもそも俺たちが
何で執行官なんぞにされたのかと
Stop right there!
止まれ
Stay back!
来るな～
Drop your guns!
銃を捨てろ
Step back!
下がれ
Die!
死ね
あっ　なっ 何だ　こりゃ
Wh-What the hell is this?!
ご愁傷さま
My deepest sympathies.
This is Hound 3. Enforcement completed.
ハウンド３ 執行完了
Using an old man and a newbie as a decoy, eh?
年寄りと新米をおとりにするとは
You sure got cojones, don't you, Ko?
いい根性してんな
ええ　コウ
Just earning my paycheck, pops.
給料分の仕事だろ　とっつあん
We're with the Public Safety Bureau.
公安局です もう大丈夫　安心してください
You're safe now. Please rest at ease.
Calm down!
落ち着いて あなたを助けに来たのよ
We came to rescue you!
No... No...
嫌　やめて
Don't...
Please don't...
やめて
Masaoka...
征陸さん
Young lady...
お嬢ちゃん
check her with your gun.
銃で確かめてみろ
Crime Coefficient is over 160.
「犯罪係数　オーバー１６０」
She's a target for enforcement action.
「執行対象です」
Well, I guess we have no choice.
まあ　仕方ないわな
Stop it!
やめて
No! Nooooo!
嫌っ 嫌
The hell's wrong with you?!
何をする
We should be protecting her!
あの人は　保護対象です
そのためのパラライザーだろうが
That's exactly why the Paralyzer exists!
今すぐ眠らせて確保するんだ
We'll put her to sleep right away and take her into custody!
She's just confused!
彼女は混乱してるだけです
You don't have to use violence on her!
そんな乱暴なことしなくても
Listen. The Dominators are Sibyl's eyes.
いいか ドミネーターはシビュラの目だ
This town's system itself has decided that she's a threat!
この街のシステムそのものが彼女を脅威と判断したんだ
Think about what that means!
その意味を考えろ
So you'd shoot a victim who hasn't even committed a crime yet?!
だからって
何もしてない被害者を撃つなんてそんなの納得できません
I can't accept that!
Stay away... Don't come any closer.
来ないで もう近寄らないで
Stop it already...
もう　やめて
あっ　もう
I-I said stay away!
もう　もう　来んなよ!
Kougami!
狡噛さん
Please don't.
やめてください
Please!
お願いです
She's the victim here!
彼女は被害者で
Target's Threat Judgement has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Enforcement mode is Lethal Eliminator.
「執行モード リーサル·エリミネーター」
Aim carefully and eliminate the target.
「慎重に照準を定め 対象を排除してください」
No...
そんな
Don't!
やめて
あっ　ああ
Please stop.
もうやめて
Throw that lighter away.
そのライターを捨てて
Or... this gun will kill you.
でないと この銃があなたを殺しちゃう
Please! I want to help you!
お願い　あなたを助けたいの
So throw that lighter away.
だからライターを捨てて
Target's Threat Judgement has been updated.
「対象の脅威判定が更新されました」
Enforcement mode is Non-Lethal Paralyzer.
「執行モード ノンリーサル·パラライザー」
Aim calmly and bring the target under control.
「落ち着いて照準を定め 対象を制圧してください」
Inspector Tsunemori.
I'll expect you to thoroughly explain
your handling of this situation in your report.
Fearii teeru wa
It seems all fairy tales
This newbie we got sure is a piece of work.
Sakki shinda mitai
Are dead
Renga no byoutou de
In a hospital ward of brick stones
Umaku utaenakute
My voice is too coarse to sing
Kiri ni kemuru yoru
Outside in the foggy haze
Ukabe akai tsuki
A red moon glows
Hora mite watashi wo
Look at me
Me wo sorasanai de
Do not avert your gaze
Kuroi tetsu goushi no naka de
Behind black bars
Watashi wa umarete kitanda
I was born
Kuroi tetsu goushi no naka de
Behind black bars
I was born
Watashi wa umarete kitanda
Akui no daishou wo negae
I wish there were a punishment for evil
Watashi wa umarete kitanda
I was born
I wish there were a punishment for evil
Akui no daishou wo negae
Nozomu ga mama ni omae ni
Always I need you
Akui no daishou wo negae
I wish there were a punishment for evil
Always I need you
Nozomu ga mama ni omae ni
Saa ataeyou seigi wo
Now, grant us justice
Nozomu ga mama ni omae ni
Always I need you
Now, grant us justice
Saa ataeyou seigi wo
Kowashite kowasareru mae ni
Before chaos takes us all
Saa ataeyou seigi wo
Now, grant us justice
Before chaos takes us all
Kowashite kowasareru mae ni
Inga no daishou wo harai mukui yo na mo
Pay the price of fate and be rewarded,
Kowashite kowasareru mae ni
Before chaos takes us all
Pay the price of fate and be rewarded,
Inga no daishou wo harai mukui yo na mo
常守監視官 君の状況判断については
Naki kaibutsu
Nameless beast
Inga no daishou wo harai mukui yo na mo
Pay the price of fate and be rewarded,
Nameless beast
Naki kaibutsu
報告書できっちりと説明してもらう
Kuroi ame furase kono sora
Black rain falls from the sky
Naki kaibutsu
Nameless beast
Black rain falls from the sky
Kuroi ame furase kono sora
Watashi wa nozomarenai mono
And I remain forever unwanted
Kuroi ame furase kono sora
Black rain falls from the sky
And I remain forever unwanted
Watashi wa nozomarenai mono
Hibiwareta noirooze
My crazed neurosis
Watashi wa nozomarenai mono
And I remain forever unwanted
My crazed neurosis
Hibiwareta noirooze
こりゃ
とんでもない新人が来ちまったもんだな
Aisu douzai no boukanshatachi ni
Pulls me towards the sinful hellfire
Hibiwareta noirooze
My crazed neurosis
Pulls me towards the sinful hellfire
Aisu douzai no boukanshatachi ni
Saa ima furue seigi wo
Now, mete out justice
Aisu douzai no boukanshatachi ni
Pulls me towards the sinful hellfire
Now, mete out justice
Saa ima furue seigi wo
Kesenai kizu wo dakishimete
Even my ever-bleeding wounds shall be my friend
Saa ima furue seigi wo
Now, mete out justice
Even my ever-bleeding wounds shall be my friend
Kesenai kizu wo dakishimete
Kono karada wo ukeire tomo ni yukou
Let's accept who we are and walk together
Kesenai kizu wo dakishimete
Even my ever-bleeding wounds shall be my friend
Let's accept who we are and walk together
Kono karada wo ukeire tomo ni yukou
Namae no nai kaibutsu
We, who are nameless beasts
Kono karada wo ukeire tomo ni yukou
Let's accept who we are and walk together
We, who are nameless beasts
Namae no nai kaibutsu
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all individuals and organizations that appear
in this show are fictitious and any similarity to those in existence in the real world is purely coincidental.
This is a world where the mental state and personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed, these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass".
This story is a work of fiction. The names of all individuals and organizations that appear
in this show are fictitious and any similarity to those in existence in the real world is purely coincidental.
This is a world where the mental state and personal tendencies of humans can be quantified.
While all sorts of inclinations are recorded and policed, these measured numbers used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass".
Namae no nai kaibutsu
We, who are nameless beasts